usni.org 2007-03-29

# U.S. Naval Institute: Privacy Statement

| 

This Privacy Statement sets forth the information gathering, use, and dissemination practices of the U.S. Naval Institute ("We" or the "Naval Institute") in connection with the World Wide Web Site located at [www.usni.org](http://www.usni.org/) (the "Site"). This Privacy Statement addresses our practices regarding information collected only directly through or from the Site-it does not address or govern any information gathering, use, or dissemination practices related to information collected other than directly through or from the Site, including, without limitation, from or via telephone, facsimile, postal mail, personal delivery, or other or additional offline means or media.

If you have any questions or concerns regarding the Naval Institute's privacy policy, please direct them to [privacy@usni.org](mailto:privacy@usni.org). You may also send a letter to: 

Web Site Privacy Officer  
U.S. Naval Institute  
291 Wood Road  
Annapolis, MD 21402 

What Information Is Collected?

**When browsing our Site:** Except as otherwise provided in this Privacy Statement, we collect no personally identifiable information from users from their mere browsing of the Site. We collect only aggregate data (such as the number of views per page or advertisement during a given period of time) from mere browsing activity of Site users.

**Domain Names:** When you visit the Site, our Web server automatically logs the domain name of your Internet service provider. This information is stored in our server logs.

**Registered Users:** To become a registered user of the Site, you must supply us with the information we need to process your request. This information may include your name, e-mail address, and a password, as well as your rank, service branch, and address (if applicable).

**Ordering Merchandise:** If you use our secure online server to order merchandise, we ask that you submit information needed to process the order. This information may include, for example, your name, shipping address, telephone number, credit card number, and e-mail address.

**eForum Participants:** Guest users in the eForum section of the www.navalinstitute.org Site need provide no information to access the eForum and read posts. To post comments or remarks in the discussion boards within the eForum, you must sign up within the eForum section of the Site (a separate process from becoming a registered Site user). To sign up for eForum, you may be asked to provide your name, e-mail address, and a password, among other information. Remember that any information you post when participating in the eForum, including your e-mail address, is publicly available. See the [eForum Terms and Guidelines](http://eforum.usni.org/eforum?14@@.ee96acf) for more information.

**Becoming a Member of the Naval Institute:** When you [join](https://www.usni.org/accounts/membershipwizard/member1.htm) the Naval Institute using our secure online membership form, we request certain information of you, which may include, for example, your name, address, phone number, date of birth, and e-mail address, your rank and service branch (if applicable), and credit card information. It is your option to note how you heard about the Naval Institute.

**E-mails from the Naval Institute:** To receive e-mails from the Naval Institute, you must provide us with your e-mail address, and may also be required to provide your rank, service branch, year of birth, and address. We may monitor which links you click on, time and date of clicks, and destination pages; this information is personally identifiable.

How Is the Information Used?

**Identifiable Information:** We may use information you voluntarily provide to us through any of the means described above to communicate with you about the transaction(s) you wish to execute, are executing, or have executed with us, to process and fulfill such transaction(s), and to notify you of other products or services of the Naval Institute or third parties in which we believe you may be interested. In addition, we may provide information you voluntarily provided to us through any of the means described above (but only non-credit card information) to third parties to provide you opportunities to receive third-party products or services or information about relevant products or services. We also may use information you voluntarily provide to us to help us customize Site content, to provide you a personalized and efficient Site visit, or to notify you of changes to the Site, Site policies and practices, and Site rules and requirements.

**Non-Identifiable Information:** We use non-personally identifiable data collected by us (such as the number of views per page or advertisement during a given period of time) for internal and marketing purposes, including, for example, to aggregate and review Site usage patterns.

We use "cookies" to make it easier for registered users of the Site to return to areas of interest on the Site. If a registered user consents by checking a "Remember me" box or similar device, we store a cookie on their computer that permits them to enter the Site without logging in each time. If the user does not check such a box, the user will be required to log in each time they visit the Site.

**Identifiable and Non-Identifiable Information:** Additionally, identifiable or non-identifiable data may be disclosed or distributed to a third party (a) pursuant to a subpoena, court order, or other form of legal process, (b) in response to a request by or on behalf of any local, state, federal, or other government agency, department, or body, whether or not pursuant to a subpoena, court order, or other form of legal process, or (c) if determined by us in our sole judgment that such disclosure or distribution is appropriate to protect the life, health, or property of us or any other person or entity. 

While we may undertake efforts to see that any third party to or with which we share, rent, sell, or otherwise disclose personal data is under a contractual obligation to use the personal data solely for the purposes for which the data was disclosed, we are not responsible for their conduct, actions, omissions, or information handling or dissemination practices.

These Site may contain links to other World Wide Web sites or advertisements for or placed by third parties. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of such Web sites, advertisers, or third parties, or for the content of such sites or advertisements. It is possible that these links or advertisements themselves may be used by third parties or others to collect personal or other information about Site visitors. It is solely the user's obligation to review and understand the privacy practices and policies of these other Web sites and of these advertisers and third parties.

Security

We have implemented numerous security features designed to prevent the unauthorized release of or access to personal information. For example, your credit card information is transmitted to us via the Site using the industry standard, SSL (secure socket layer) encryption. Please be advised, however, that the confidentiality of any communication or material transmitted to or from us via these Site or e-mail cannot be guaranteed. Accordingly, we are not responsible for the security of information transmitted via the Internet. Site users who do not wish to communicate with us via e-mail or the Internet can contact us by mail at the address near the beginning of this Privacy Statement.

"Tell a Friend about This Page" Feature

When you use the "Tell a friend about this page" feature of the Site, we store both your and your friend's email address and may use them as outlined in "Identifiable Information" above.

Opt Out

You may opt out of receiving Naval Institute or third-party offers when you register on the Site, order merchandise, become a member, or subscribe to or receive e-mail newsletters. If you choose, you may opt out of all marketing-related communication from the Naval Institute. If you prefer not to receive marketing-related mailings or emails, U.S. and Canadian customers may call 800-233-8764. All customers may write us, at Naval Institute, 291 Wood Road, Annapolis, MD 21402 or e-mail us at [privacy@usni.org](mailto:privacy@usni.org). You may also go to the Opt Out area of your [user profile page](https://www.usni.org/accounts/index.asp). 

User Age Restrictions

Users of this Site acknowledge that they are at least 18 years of age.

Access to and Ability to Correct Personal Data

Upon a Site user's request via postal mail or e-mail, we will provide to the user a summary of any personally identifiable information retained by us regarding the user, which information has been voluntarily provided to us through an online form, registration form, survey, or other similar mechanism. A registered user may modify, correct, change or update their personally identifiable information online with this feature: <https://www.usni.org/accounts/index.asp>, or may contact us via postal mail or e-mail at the addresses or numbers above. 

Right to Amend Privacy Statement

We reserve the right to revise this Privacy Statement from time to time, in our sole discretion. Any changes to this Privacy Statement will be posted to this page as soon as reasonably possible, for at least 60 days. It is the obligation of users visiting the Site before the change to learn of changes to the Privacy Statement since their last visit. Use of the Naval Institute Web Site constitutes consent to any Privacy Statement then in effect.

Questions? Please contact us at [privacy@usni.org](mailto:privacy@usni.org) or the street address identified near the beginning of this Privacy Statement.

This Privacy Statement is effective 7 March 2005.

back to top

|   
---|---
